<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>syd the kid</title>
    <link>https://banjoboy.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on syd the kid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 20:18:30 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://banjoboy.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>lessons on love from kitties</title>
      <link>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/lessons-from-kitties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 20:18:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/lessons-from-kitties/</guid>
      <description>I have been waking up to a new alarm recently. Consistently at 7am, Gobi, black and poised, sends faint meows thru my bedroom door. I imagine that she sits in the center of the archway, perched with her straight-backed posture that anyone would envy, wrapping her delicate tail around her legs for all of her regular twenty plus minutes of meowing. But as soon as I find my way up and open the door, she runs to my feet, circles my ankles, nuzzles my toes, and flips onto her back, her delicate poise turned into urgency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[for devs] may you always unblock yourself: a few problem solving techniques</title>
      <link>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/problem-solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 13:45:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/problem-solving/</guid>
      <description>as an everything-feels-new software developer, i return to this list of questions OFTEN when i am just completely stuck or even during the thousand moments during a day when i am just trying to figure out what the next step should be. i developed this list of questions during my first professional experience as a software developer with my tech lead, Karan Krishnani.
i am a firm believer that one of the most important parts of being a good software developer (and maybe just being good at anything&amp;hellip;lmk your thoughts on that) is knowing how to ask the right questions and figure out what you don&amp;rsquo;t know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a break down of Zuboff&#39;s The Age of Surveillance Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/surveillance-capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:39:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/surveillance-capitalism/</guid>
      <description>ok you may have heard the term &amp;ldquo;Surveillance Capitalism&amp;rdquo; dropped in the last year and increasingly in the last months as Netflix dropped its new dramatic documentary The Social Dilemma and my girl Shoshana Zuboff who coined this term in her new influential monster of a book The Age of Surveillance Capitalism: The Fight For A Human Future At The Frontier of Power shows up all over the news and social webs to talk about her new framework to describe a huge amalgam of our latest technical concerns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a review of Alice Walker&#39;s Living by the Word</title>
      <link>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/living-by-the-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 16:20:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/living-by-the-word/</guid>
      <description>Every once and a while, I read a book that reminds me of the forces outside myself, the power I have over myself but not other others, and the tender way that I want to live with beings of the world — humans, plants, animals, and processes like the rising and setting of the sun. This is one of those books. Alice Walker has come into my life once again, just like she did when I picked up The Color Purple last year, when I needed this message, for which I am grateful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a review of Anna Wiener&#39;s Uncanny Valley: A Memoir</title>
      <link>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/uncanny-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 11:22:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/uncanny-valley/</guid>
      <description>As a fresh college graduate, a young woman, working my first job as a software developer, Anna Wiener in Uncanny Valley: A Memoir put words to many of my own internal doubts and hesitant enjoyment of this new world. Wiener&amp;rsquo;s story follows her from underpaid and overworked in the New York publishing industry to perhaps overpaid and overqualified in San Francisco&amp;rsquo;s Silicon Valley in various customer support roles to ultimately unemployed by choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>best albums 2020 so far</title>
      <link>https://banjoboy.net/playlists/best-albums-2020-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 16:09:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://banjoboy.net/playlists/best-albums-2020-so-far/</guid>
      <description>in no particular order&amp;hellip;
Kingdom in My Mind, The Wood Brothers Notable Mentions... - &amp;quot;Little Bit Sweet&amp;quot; - &amp;quot;The One I Love&amp;quot;  Bad for You, The Steeldrivers Notable Mentions... - &amp;quot;I Choose You&amp;quot; - love song that shows the beauty of commitment in love - &amp;quot;Glad I&#39;m Gone&amp;quot; - Steeldrivers never disappoint with a classic breakup song once again - &amp;quot;Mama Says No&amp;quot; - an instrumental that is definetely inspired by the feeling of when mama says no - &amp;quot;Lonely and Being Alone&amp;quot; - like they say, &amp;quot;there&#39;s a difference between being lonely and being alone&amp;quot; and that&#39;s never felt more true to me in these COVID times  Devotion, Margaret Glaspy Notable Mentions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the quality of country</title>
      <link>https://banjoboy.net/playlists/the-quality-of-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 12:15:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://banjoboy.net/playlists/the-quality-of-country/</guid>
      <description>a collection of thoughts on what makes country music
 &amp;ldquo;the things we believe in but cannot see&amp;rdquo; - Merle Haggard &amp;ldquo;the most popular [country] songs often were a kind of southern gothic in love with tragedy and topography&amp;rdquo; - Rebecca Solnit, A Field Guide to Getting Lost, 114 &amp;ldquo;love songs about places&amp;rdquo; - Rebecca Solnit, A Field Guide to Getting Lost, 117 &amp;ldquo;failure to connect&amp;rdquo; - Rebecca Solnit, A Field Guide to Getting Lost, 116 &amp;ldquo;irrecoverable time, irrecoverable loss and error&amp;rdquo; - Rebecca Solnit, A Field Guide to Getting Lost, 116 &amp;ldquo;tragic songs about failure of human love&amp;rdquo; - Rebecca Solnit, A Field Guide to Getting Lost, 117 &amp;ldquo;the blues defined a kind of perpetual internal exile of people who couldn&amp;rsquo;t go back, though leaving the south is a subject of a lot of blues songs, without white country music&amp;rsquo;s hankering for the places left behind.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>