<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thoughts on syd the kid</title>
    <link>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thoughts on syd the kid</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 13:32:42 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[dev shit] may you always unblock yourself: a few problem solving techniques</title>
      <link>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/problem-solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 13:45:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/problem-solving/</guid>
      <description>as an everything-feels-new software developer, i return to this list of questions OFTEN when i am just completely stuck or even during the thousand moments during a day when i am just trying to figure out what the next step should be. i developed this list of questions during my first professional experience as a software developer with my tech lead, Karan Krishnani.
i am a firm believer that one of the most important parts of being a good software developer (and maybe just being good at anything&amp;hellip;lmk your thoughts on that) is knowing how to ask the right questions and figure out what you don&amp;rsquo;t know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a break down of Zuboff&#39;s The Age of Surveillance Capitalism</title>
      <link>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/surveillance-capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:39:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/surveillance-capitalism/</guid>
      <description>ok you may have heard the term &amp;ldquo;Surveillance Capitalism&amp;rdquo; dropped in the last year and increasingly in the last months as Netflix dropped its new dramatic documentary The Social Dilemma and my girl Shoshana Zuboff who coined this term in her new influential monster of a book The Age of Surveillance Capitalism: The Fight For A Human Future At The Frontier of Power shows up all over the news and social webs to talk about her new framework to describe a huge amalgam of our latest technical concerns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a review of Alice Walker&#39;s Living by the Word</title>
      <link>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/living-by-the-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 16:20:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/living-by-the-word/</guid>
      <description>Every once and a while, I read a book that reminds me of the forces outside myself, the power I have over myself but not other others, and the tender way that I want to live with beings of the world — humans, plants, animals, and processes like the rising and setting of the sun. This is one of those books. Alice Walker has come into my life once again, just like she did when I picked up The Color Purple last year, when I needed this message, for which I am grateful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a review of Anna Wiener&#39;s Uncanny Valley: A Memoir</title>
      <link>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/uncanny-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 11:22:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://banjoboy.net/thoughts/uncanny-valley/</guid>
      <description>As a fresh college graduate, a young woman, working my first job as a software developer, Anna Wiener in Uncanny Valley: A Memoir put words to many of my own internal doubts and hesitant enjoyment of this new world. Wiener&amp;rsquo;s story follows her from underpaid and overworked in the New York publishing industry to perhaps overpaid and overqualified in San Francisco&amp;rsquo;s Silicon Valley in various customer support roles to ultimately unemployed by choice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>